rbs.co.uk 2006-12-24

# RBS: Privacy Policy

### Privacy

We (The Royal Bank of Scotland plc) are committed to protecting your privacy during your visits to the Royal Bank website and recognise our responsibility to keep the information you provide to us confidential at all times.

We protect your personal information on the Internet to an equivalent high standard to that you experience through any other channels through which we may interact with you, such as our branches, cash machines or on the telephone.

The Royal Bank of Scotland plc is a member of The Royal Bank of Scotland Group of companies and your personal information will not be disclosed outside the Group except in circumstances advised to you at the time you apply for a product or service.

### Security

Strict security procedures are followed in the storage and disclosure of your personal information.

When personal information is requested on-line by us, we ensure that your browser encrypts it. The strongest available encryption under the industry standard technology called SSL ("Secure Sockets Layer") is applied. The same technology is used for personal information sent back to your browser from the Royal Bank website.

**Your Information On-line**

### 1\. Cookies

A ‘cookie’ is information that a website stores on your computer so that it can remember something about you at a later time. Cookies are commonly used on the Internet and do not harm your system.

The cookies used on the Royal Bank website do not include any information that others could read and understand about you, such as your name or account numbers.

We currently use a combination of first party, third party, permanent and temporary cookies in the following ways:

  * To collate general, non-personal management information which is used to plan enhancements to our services. For example, cookies help us to understand the popular paths that users take through the Royal Bank website and how often people visit. Some of our general management information is collected using third party tracking code provided by Red Sheriff. We do not share information with other companies that use the same third party tracking code or combine any data collected by Red Sheriff with any personal information collected on the Royal Bank website. For more information about how Red Sheriff collects data, please read the [Red Sheriff Privacy Policy](http://www.redsheriff.com/uk/content/privacy_1.html).  
 
  * To evaluate the effectiveness of our advertising and promotions on third party websites, we use DoubleClick and Bluestreak as an agent for promotion delivery and measurement. The Bank owns the anonymous data that is collected and it is not shared with DoubleClick, Bluestreak, or any other third party. For more information about how DoubleClick and Bluestreak collects data, please read the [ DoubleClick Privacy Policy](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/corporate/privacy/privacy/default.asp?asp_object_1=&) and [ Bluestreak Privacy Policy](http://www.bluestreak.com/privacy.asp).     

  * As a flag to help us recognise when we have already asked you to participate in any on-line market research and to prevent you from being asked to complete the same questionnaire everytime that you visit the Royal Bank website.

If you do not want us to use cookies when you visit the Royal Bank website, you can configure your browser not to accept them or opt-out. Please refer to your browser’s ‘help’ facility, [Red Sheriff](http://www.redsheriff.com/uk/content/privacy_1.html) or [ DoubleClick](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/corporate/privacy/privacy/default.asp?asp_object_1=&) for further information.

### 2\. Application Information

When you apply for a product or service on the Royal Bank website, you will be asked for personal information that is needed to process your application.

The information that you provide will only be used for the purposes described at the time of your application and where applicable in the Terms and Conditions that apply to the relevant product or service. For example, in accordance with standard banking practice, we will tell you that we will provide information about you to credit reference and fraud prevention agencies.

### 3\. Digital Banking - Banking Instructions

You can use our secure Digital Banking service to access your account with us.

When you do so we ensure that your instructions are provided to us in a secure and confidential manner after you have identified yourself by "logging in" to Digital Banking.

Information that you provide, or that we can ascertain from the history of on-line transactions that you undertake using the service, will only be used to carry out your instructions and for the purposes described when you register/apply for Digital Banking and in the Terms and Conditions that apply to your account.
